yes we are going to get into our first
topic our first class and I just want to
share a couple of things very briefly
this is a class that I'm gonna be doing
every week alright it's gonna be the
same time so Tuesday 4:30 this is going
to be a weekly thing I have another
class that is basically along the same
lines but it is a more in-depth class so
this class is kind of like my Bible
study light version and for those of you
in the Facebook group the photo theology
Facebook group we're gonna be going
through some very specific things that
are going to help you to go deeper into
the scriptures so for my Instagram
people as well this is also being
streamed on YouTube I want you to just
be aware that this will be happening
every week we're gonna be going in depth
into the scriptures we're gonna be
looking at a principle called photo
theology photo theology is the art of
studying the Bible through the use of
images okay it's the art of studying the
Bible through the use of pictures
through the use of images and we're
gonna basically break this principle
down in a way that you will be able to I
believe revolutionize the way you study
the scriptures now we're not gonna spend
a whole lot of time like this this class
is gonna be probably about 15 to 20
minutes so there's these are gonna be
nuggets right but these are gonna be
heavy nuggets you're gonna be able to
break down scriptures in a way that you
probably thought you could never do
we're gonna see that in real time we're
gonna as I said even though this is
gonna be short sessions you're gonna be
able to gain an understanding of
Scripture and to pull things from the
Bible that you may not have seen before
all right so let me go ahead and share
with you what photo theology is okay so
what is this art that we call photo
theology photo theology is basically the
art of studying the Bible through the
use of images through the use of
pictures so I don't know if any of you
ever remembered playing ever played a
card game when you were younger and that
game was called concentration and
basically the object of that card game
was very simple you had to find a match
to a card you had seen before all the
cards were turned over facing downward
on the deck you have to turn the card
over and then you had to remember where
you saw a match for that card right the
object of the game was to find the
matching cards all right
Bible study is very much like that card
game called concentration okay
and especially with this art of photo
theology it is the art of taking
pictures in the Bible and comparing
those pictures with other pictures in
the Bible this is basically the essence
of the way that I study the scriptures
in particular right it's simply
comparing pictures with pictures now
you've probably heard the saying that a
picture is worth a thousand words right
if you've heard that saying it's a very
powerful thing right you can gain more
from a picture then you can
many words describing that picture well
photo theology operates off of the same
principle instead of focusing merely on
the words of a page of the page you're
taking those words and translating them
as it were into images and when you can
begin to compare image to image what you
see is things be that begin to pop out
on the page right so for example take
the story of Samson okay this is one of
my favorite stories this is the story
you all are pretty much familiar but
Samson
is betrayed by a woman that he loves he
is beaten he is bound he is bruised he
is mocked he's taken between two pillars
place his hands on those pillars the
Bible says that he bowed his head and
pushed and when he pushed there was a
great rumbling all right now I've just
given you in a juice down format the
story of Samson however if I would ask
you does this story of Samson remind you
of anything else you have heard in the
Bible anything else you have seen in the
Bible you would probably begin to go
wait a minute wait a minute that sounds
very familiar and why would you say that
sounds familiar because you're probably
thinking about Jesus who was betrayed by
a woman that he loved the church who was
beaten bruised mocked bound and then
placed between two crosses and the Bible
says that he bowed his head and gave up
the ghost when he died there was a great
rumbling just as when Samson died there
was a great rumbling
and there is a difference Samson slayed
more in his debt than when he was alive
but Jesus saved more in his death than
when he was alive all right so what just
happened that very simply is photo
theology right we just took two
different stories two images right two
pictures and compared those pictures and
found a match so just as we talked about
the card game you turn the cards are all
facing down when you flip the card you
see a picture you try to remember where
it I see that picture before where'd I
see something like this before
you find that when you find the match
it's an aha moment that's what we're
looking for we're looking for aha
moments in the scriptures where we begin
to see what I like to call divine design
right in other words you begin to see
that these stories were not simply
placed in the Bible by accident right
every story every story in the Bible has
some relevance to some other portion of
the scripture in other words the Bible
is divinely designed okay so one of the
first principles that I want to share
with you is basically this how do I get
pictures in my mind and really that's
very simple most of you if you if you
have studied the Bible at all if you
grew up as a Christian you have a lot of
pictures hanging in your mind what I
what what is called elsewhere memories
Hall the more pictures you have hanging
in memories Hall the more effective and
more powerful your Bible study is going
to be right so how do you get those
pictures hanging in memories Hall it's
very simple but read the Bible listen to
Bible stories write anything you can do
to get the stories of the Bible
into your mind think of your mind as a
hallway and that hallway should have
pictures of all these stories of the
Bible hanging there if you don't have
these pictures hanging in memories Hall
your Bible study is going to suffer at
least when it comes to using photo
theology as a method so what you want to
do is you want to begin to practice
placing pictures in memories Hall the
more pictures you have hanging there the
more powerful your Bible study is gonna
be that means you want to try to
memorize scriptures you want to try to
memorize stories and listen even if you
don't understand what the story means
that's okay because what will happen
what begins to happen when you begin
using this style of Bible study is you
might be minding your business totally
doing something just you know just
minding your business and all of a
sudden the Holy Spirit will match to
pictures hanging in your Hall pictures
that you never thought would have had
anything to do with one another and
that's when you get that aha moment
right that's what we're after we're
after learning how to begin to compare
Scripture with Scripture or picture with
picture and when you begin to do this
books like Revelation books like Daniel
books like Ezekiel in fact let me just
lit the whole Bible will begin to jump
off the page okay and that is what
you're after you want the Bible to come
to life when you study it okay photo
theology is in essence training your
mind how to see the big picture training
your mind how to step back from the
Bible and see it from a bird's eye view
versus seeing it like in the forest a
lot of times we get up close and
personal to the tree and we're trying to
understand the
three when really what we ought to be
doing is stepping back from the tree and
looking at the forest to catch the big
picture okay so I want to give you an
example of a big picture what I mean by
a big picture so most of you know what
what it means when you juice something
right you take a bunch of fruits you
take a bunch of vegetables whatever it
is you put it in the juicer and what the
juicer does is it it transforms all
those vegetables into a state that you
could take them all in whereas before
you could not but you can't eat it'll be
difficult to eat 20 vegetables but if
you do sit down you can drink it no
problem
photo Theology basically teaches you how
to juice the Scriptures down so when
you're looking at things like the book
of Revelation or the book of Daniel
once again the prophecies of the Bible
you can a lot of times people just get
overwhelmed I can't understand it you
know I don't know how to make sense this
when you can step back look at the big
picture and learn how to juice a text
learn how to juice an entire book learn
how to juice the entire Bible the Old
Testament or the New Testament it gives
you a confidence write it in it it helps
you to come to the Bible thinking you
know what with the aid of the Holy
Spirit
I can understand this book right it's
not as difficult as I think it is and
that's where I want you to get to I want
you to get to the place where you can
start to go through the Book of Daniel
or Revelation the prophecies of the
Bible the Gospels of the epistles you
can begin to go through these books for
yourself and understand them for
yourself okay
that's gonna be the goal of this class
you being able to understand this for
yourself all right so here's what I'm
going to do I'm going to I'm gonna give
you an example of what it means to juice
something and then I'm gonna give you an
assignment all right and then we're
gonna wrap it up so I like I told you
this class is gonna be short I see some
of you may have been having trouble
getting on don't worry about it this
will be posted to the Facebook group and
hopefully we won't have this issue the
next time we air which would be next
Tuesday but I'm gonna give you one
example and then I'm gonna give you an
assignment okay so here we go we are
about to juice down the entire Old
Testament and we're gonna do it in just
a few minutes are you ready all right so
I'm gonna watch for your response here
and I know that there's a little delay
so I'm gonna wait for your response but
I'm going to ask you a question here's a
question how many offices were there in
the Old Testament how many offices were
there in the Old Testament all right so
I'm looking on my Instagram feed here
and I'm looking at my Facebook and I
just want to see what you guys are what
your answers are how many offices in the
Old Testament when I say offices I hope
you understand what I mean right
I'll give you a hint one of them would
be profit so in the Old Testament there
were prophets okay so what are the other
offices in the in the Old Testament
any clues all right very good so I see
if someone said judges okay so judges
was another office of the Old Testament
so we had prophets we have judges
therefore four offices so what were the
other two offices of the okay very good
so I see priests and there is one more
one more office so we got priests
already we've got judges we've got
prophets and we have see if anybody very
good we got Kings all right
so those are the four offices there's
Kings its prophets its judges they're
priests all right now check this out
guys this is what happens when you begin
to utilize the art of photo theology it
teaches you how to step back how to look
at the big picture how to see images
right how to translate what you're
reading into images and then how to
compare those images concentration
matching game alright so watch this if I
were to ask you to give me the order in
which those offices were magnified in
the Bible right the order in which they
were we might say introduced or focused
on in the Bible what would the order be
okay so we're Kings introduced first the
Kings the obvious answer is no because
you don't really see an emphasis of
Kings until we get to the book of first
and second Samuel book in first first
second Kings right so here's a question
what office was magnified first I'm
going to wait to see if I can a look at
your answers here what office was
magnified first
okay I'm watching for your answers let's
see okay very good profits someone said
the office of profits were magnified
first very good so you think of you
think of Noah right as a profit you
think of Joseph as a profit you think of
Enoch as a profit so the profits were
the first office to me to be magnified
or brought to the forefront in the
scripture specifically the book of
Genesis tell us about the product of the
prophets okay now what was the next
office that would have been magnified in
the scriptures and some of you are
already catching this right the next
office to be magnified in the scriptures
you got it Marshall was the office of
the priesthood the office of the priest
okay so we obviously are thinking of the
book of Exodus and Leviticus and numbers
right this is where you have an emphasis
of the of the priests this is where we
are introduced to the Levitical
priesthood okay so I'm not saying that
priests were not mentioned before the
book of Exodus I'm simply saying that it
was magnified the priesthood came to the
forefront
after prophets okay very good so we've
got prophets and then we've got priests
very good I see you guys following on
facebook all right now what was the next
office to be magnified in the scriptures
after prophet after priest what would
have been the next office to be
magnified so think priests right Exodus
Leviticus numbers Deuteronomy Joshua
that's all about the priesthood what
would be the next office to be magnified
and all you got to do is think of what
book comes after Joshua very good judges
judges the judges was the next office to
be magnified in the scripture so prophet
priests judges
which means the last office obviously
was the office of what the office of the
Kings right and so this is where we now
have a first and second Samuel first and
second Kings first and second Chronicles
right from here on out you're dealing
with the kings of Israel right this is
pretty much a summarization of the
entire Old Testament right
we know that the Kings ultimately
totally failed and messed up however and
and then the Kings were work work cut
off as it were but this is the order
watch this prophet priest judge King
prophet priest judge King do you see
what the scripture is doing here because
once I start to think about that order
huh prophet priest judge king prophet
priest judge king let me visualize that
let me put that into it let me translate
that into an image and when I translate
that into an image a picture suddenly
suddenly I got my deck my deck of
pictures all turned down and suddenly
I'm remembering something wait a minute
prophet priest judge king prophet priest
judge King I've seen this picture
somewhere else before and the place that
I have seen it is in the person of Jesus
Christ who came to this earth as a
prophet died was buried resurrected and
ascended to heaven as our high priest
we know that at some point in his
priestly ministry a judgment begin
that judgment begins before the second
coming but at the end of that judgment
he returns as king of kings and Lord of
lords I want you guys to see what just
happened we just took the entire Old
Testament broke it juiced it down into
four categories prophets priests judges
kings those were the four offices of the
Old Testament and then we compared and
said wait a minute there's a match here
and basically the entire Old Testament
is showing us Christ as prophet Christ
as priest Christ as judge Christ as king
of kings and Lord that's the entire Old
Testament we just used it down all right
now this shows us something absolutely
mind-blowing because I want you to check
this out check out what photo theology
helps us to see did God ordained for
prophets yes he did he ordained for
prophets and he ordained for prophets
because the prophets were to were to be
a type of Christ as prophet are you
catching this all right
they Christ ordained the priesthood that
Christ Himself Institute the priesthood
that God Himself instituted the
priesthood yes he did why because the
priests were to represent a time where
to be a symbol or a type of Jesus as our
high priest yes yes yes okay did God
Institute the judges himself yes God
instituted the judges himself why
because the judges were to be a type of
Jesus in judgment all right
you know what I'm going next right did
Christ
stitute the kings of Israel
yes or no I got away from our Facebook
people to catch up because there's a 20
second lag but I just I'm just gonna
wait I know on Instagram you're you're
you're following this a little bit
faster than than the Facebook group but
did Christ Institute the Office of the
Kings for Israel the answer is no no no
no no no no mass your question where
they're good prophets many good prophets
right some bad prophets but many good
prophets where they're good judges yes
great I mean I'm a priest I'm sorry good
priests yes
great priests some bad priests but but a
lot of good priests were there good
judges yes yes good judges some judges
questioned well but mostly good judges
what about the Kings were there good
Kings yeah like one or two by far the
Kings failed miserably
why because you can reflect Christ as
priest man can do that you can reflect
Christ as prophets you can reflect
Christ as judges but you cannot
represent Christ as king of kings and
Lord of lords there's only one king of
kings and Lord of lords and that is
Jesus himself the office of the King was
never designed for some man to fill that
was an office for Jesus only and now you
can understand why the Kings
failed so miserably at reflecting Christ
as king of kings and Lord of lords all
right guys what have we just done we've
just taken the entire Old Testament and
using this principle of photo theology
we juiced it down and then what we did
is we compared what we saw with with
another picture that for many of you you
already had it in memory so you didn't
have to think wait a minute is Jesus a
priest or wait a minute is Jesus a judge
or wait a minute she's a prophet no you
already knew that it was already hanging
there in memories Hall are you catching
this photo theology is the art of
learning how to step back and see the
big picture it's the art of learning how
to juice down large amounts of
information into something that is easy
to understand why because the Bible is
truly divinely designed all right guys
this is now I want you to remember this
is photo theology my light class okay
we're only on here 20 minutes I have
another class which goes an hour a week
that's a different class my patreon
class here I'm gonna try to keep it
light and I'm gonna trim because a lot
of people are in different places so
everybody's not gonna be you know I need
to take a light in this class but I want
you to see what we've done I hope you're
excited about what we just covered today
okay because I want to teach you how to
apply this principle in your own study
so that you can do what we just did you
can do it for the New Testament what we
just did you'll be able to begin to go
through scriptures go through any book
of the Bible and begin to see things
that will blow your mind because
remember a picture is worth a thousand
words all right
so guys I'm gonna end it here I was
gonna give you an assignment but I am
NOT I want to save this this next
assignment for our next class so in the
meantime I just want you to practice one
thing okay I want you to begin to think
about placing images in memories Hall
that's all I want you to do get those
stories in of the Bible into your mind
even if you're hazy about them just
start trying to the more stories you
have in your mind the more you have to
match up with your lane what's up man
good to see you anyway so that's what I
want you to do okay I just want you to
get these pictures in memories Hall and
that is going to be trust me
50% of everything we do here is gonna
depend on how many pictures you have
hanging in memories Hall alright guys so
that's it thank you for joining me on
Instagram thank you for joining me on
Facebook and YouTube if there were any
technical difficulties when you for some
reason couldn't get on till later in the
program don't don't worry about it this
will be posted on all three platforms
but specifically for now specifically if
you guys are not in the Facebook photo
theology group you need to get in that
group because this may have gone like to
my whole facebook page I'm not sure I'm
not doing that in the future okay this
is only for those that are interested in
learning how to study the Bible so go to
my photo theology group on Facebook and
just request any part of that group
answer the three questions will get you
into the group and I will look forward
to seeing you guys next Tuesday all
right until then blessings to you and
stay safe and stay healthy
peace